Fast forwarding a decade later to 2012, I was entering my third low-performing school as principal. I was to be Strawberry Mansion's fourth principal in four years. It was labeled "low-performing and persistently dangerous" due to its low test scores and high number of weapons, drugs, assaults and arrests. Shortly as I approached the door of my new school and attempted to enter, and found the door locked with chains, I could hear Ashley's voice in my ears going, "Miss! Miss! This is not a school." The halls were dim and dark from poor lighting. There were tons of piles of broken old furniture and desks in the classrooms, and there were thousands of unused materials and resources. This was not a school. As the year progressed, I noticed that the classrooms were nearly empty. The students were just scared: scared to sit in rows in fear that something would happen; scared because they were often teased in the cafeteria for eating free food. They were scared from all the fighting and all the bullying. This was not a school. And then, there were the teachers, who were incredibly afraid for their own safety, so they had low expectations for the students and themselves, and they were totally unaware of their role in the destruction of the school's culture. This was the most troubling of all. You see, Ashley was right, and not just about her school. For far too many schools, for kids who live in poverty, their schools are really not schools at all. But this can change. Let me tell you how it's being done at Strawberry Mansion High School. Anybody who's ever worked with me will tell you I am known for my slogans. (Laughter)
Adelantemos una década a 2012, yo ingresaba en mi tercera escuela de bajo rendimiento como directora. Iba a ser la cuarta directora de Strawberry Mansion en cuatro años. Fue etiquetada como: "De bajo rendimiento y persistentemente peligrosa" debido a sus bajos puntajes en los exámenes y al alto número de armas, drogas, asaltos y detenciones. Poco después de acercarme a la puerta de mi nueva escuela y tratar de entrar, encontré la puerta cerrada con cadenas, Podía oír la voz de Ashley en mis oídos diciendo, "¡Señorita! ¡Señorita! Esto no es una escuela". Los pasillos eran opacos y oscuros por una mala iluminación. Había un montón de pilas de muebles viejos dañados y pupitres en las aulas, y había miles de materiales y recursos sin usar. Eso no era una escuela. A medida que avanzaba el año, me di cuenta de que las aulas estaban casi vacías. Los estudiantes estaban asustados: asustados de sentarse en filas con temor de que algo sucediera; miedo porque eran objeto de burlas en la cafetería por comer comida gratis. Tenían miedo de todas las peleas y todo el acoso. Esto no era una escuela. Y ahí estaban los maestros, increíblemente temerosos de su propia seguridad, así que tenían bajas expectativas de los estudiantes y de ellos mismos, y eran totalmente conscientes de su papel en la destrucción de la cultura de la escuela. Este fue lo más preocupante de todo. Ya ven, Ashley estaba en lo cierto, y no solo sobre su escuela. Para demasiadas escuelas, para los niños que viven en la pobreza, sus escuelas realmente no son escuelas en absoluto. Pero esto puede cambiar. Déjenme contarles qué se está haciendo en la secundaria Strawberry Mansion. Cualquiera que haya trabajado conmigo les dirá que soy conocida por mis lemas. (Risas)
So today, I am going to use three that have been paramount in our quest for change. My first slogan is: if you're going to lead, lead. I always believed that what happens in a school and what does not happen in a school is up to the principal. I am the principal, and having that title required me to lead. I was not going to stay in my office, I was not going to delegate my work, and I was not going to be afraid to address anything that was not good for children, whether that made me liked or not. I am a leader, so I know I cannot do anything alone. So, I assembled a top-notch leadership team who believed in the possibility of all the children, and together, we tackled the small things, like resetting every single locker combination by hand so that every student could have a secure locker. We decorated every bulletin board in that building with bright, colorful, and positive messages. We took the chains off the front doors of the school. We got the lightbulbs replaced, and we cleaned every classroom to its core, recycling every, every textbook that was not needed, and discarded thousands of old materials and furniture. We used two dumpsters per day. And, of course, of course, we tackled the big stuff, like rehauling the entire school budget so that we can reallocate funds to have more teachers and support staff. We rebuilt the entire school day schedule from scratch to add a variety of start and end times, remediation, honors courses, extracurricular activities, and counseling, all during the school day. All during the school day. We created a deployment plan that specified where every single support person and police officer would be every minute of the day, and we monitored at every second of the day, and, our best invention ever, we devised a schoolwide discipline program titled "Non-negotiables." It was a behavior system -- designed to promote positive behavior at all times. The results? Strawberry Mansion was removed from the Persistently Dangerous List our first year after being -- (Applause) -- after being on the Persistently Dangerous List for five consecutive years. Leaders make the impossible possible. That brings me to my second slogan: So what? Now what? (Laughter) (Applause) When we looked at the data, and we met with the staff, there were many excuses for why Strawberry Mansion was low-performing and persistently dangerous. They said that only 68 percent of the kids come to school on a regular basis, 100 percent of them live in poverty, only one percent of the parents participate, many of the children come from incarceration and single-parent homes, 39 percent of the students have special needs, and the state data revealed that six percent of the students were proficient in algebra, and 10 were proficient in literature. After they got through telling us all the stories of how awful the conditions and the children were, I looked at them, and I said, "So what. Now what? What are we gonna do about it?" (Applause) Eliminating excuses at every turn became my primary responsibility. We addressed every one of those excuses through a mandatory professional development, paving the way for intense focus on teaching and learning. After many observations, what we determined was that teachers knew what to teach but they did not know how to teach so many children with so many vast abilities. So, we developed a lesson delivery model for instruction that focused on small group instruction, making it possible for all the students to get their individual needs met in the classroom. The results? After one year, state data revealed that our scores have grown by 171 percent in Algebra and 107 percent in literature. (Applause) We have a very long way to go, a very long way to go, but we now approach every obstacle with a "So What. Now What?" attitude. And that brings me to my third and final slogan. (Laughter) If nobody told you they loved you today, you remember I do, and I always will. My students have problems: social, emotional and economic problems you could never imagine. Some of them are parents themselves, and some are completely alone. If someone asked me my real secret for how I truly keep Strawberry Mansion moving forward, I would have to say that I love my students and I believe in their possibilities unconditionally.
Así que hoy, voy a utilizar tres que han sido de suma importancia en nuestra búsqueda del cambio. Mi primer lema es: si vas a liderar, lidera. Siempre he creído que lo que sucede y lo que no sucede en una escuela depende del director. Yo soy la directora, y tener ese título me obliga a liderar. No iba a permanecer en mi oficina, no iba a delegar mi trabajo y yo no iba a tener miedo de hacer frente a cualquier cosa que no fuera buena para los niños, me gustara o no. Yo soy una líder, así que sé que no puedo hacer nada sola. Así, reuní un equipo de liderazgo de primera categoría que creía en las posibilidades de todos los niños, y juntos, abordamos las cosas pequeñas, como restablecer todas las combinaciones de los casilleros manualmente para que cada estudiante pudiera tener un casillero seguro. Decoramos cada tablón de anuncios en ese edificio con mensajes brillantes, coloridos y positivos. Retiramos las cadenas de la puerta principal de la escuela. Reemplazamos las bombillas dañadas, y limpiamos todas las aulas a fondo, reciclando cada, cada libro de texto que no fuera necesario, y desechamos miles de materiales y muebles antiguos. Usamos dos contenedores de basura por día. Y, por supuesto, por supuesto, abordamos las cosas grandes, como reconvertir todo el presupuesto de la escuela para poder reasignar fondos para tener más profesores y personal de apoyo. Reconstruimos todo el programa diario de la escuela a partir de cero para agregar una variedad de tiempos de inicio y fin, remediales, cursos de honores, actividades extracurriculares, y asesoramiento, todo durante el día escolar. Todo durante la jornada escolar. Creamos un plan de despliegue que especificaba dónde encontrar a cada persona de apoyo y oficial de policía cada minuto del día, y monitorizábamos cada segundo del día, y, nuestra mejor invención, ideamos un programa de disciplina escolar titulado "No negociables". Era un sistema de comportamiento --diseñado para promover siempre un comportamiento positivo--. ¿Los resultados? Strawberry Mansion fue retirada de la lista de persistentemente peligrosas en nuestro primer año después de estar... (Aplausos) Tras estar en la lista de peligrosas por 5 años consecutivos. Los líderes hacen posible lo imposible. Esto me lleva a mi segundo lema: ¿Así es? Entonces, ¿qué hacemos? (Risas) (Aplausos) Cuando nos fijamos en los datos, y nos reunimos con el personal, había muchas excusas de por qué Strawberry Mansion era de bajo rendimiento y persistentemente peligrosa. Dijeron que solo el 68 % de los niños venían a la escuela de forma regular, 100 % vivían en la pobreza, solo el 1 % de los padres participaban, muchos de los niños provenían de padres encarcelados y hogares monoparentales, El 39 % de los estudiantes tenían necesidades especiales, y los datos del estado revelaron que solo el 6 % de los estudiantes eran competentes en álgebra, y el 10 % en literatura. Después de decirnos todas las historias de lo mal que estaban las condiciones y los niños, los miré, y dije: "¿Así es? Entonces, ¿qué hacemos? ¿Qué vamos a hacer al respecto?". (Aplausos) Eliminar las excusas en cada paso se convirtió en mi principal responsabilidad. Abordamos cada una de esas excusas a través de un desarrollo profesional obligatorio, allanando el camino para un enfoque intenso en la enseñanza y el aprendizaje. Después de muchas observaciones, lo que se determinó fue que los maestros sabían qué enseñar, pero no sabían cómo enseñar a tantos niños con habilidades tan dispares. Así que desarrollamos un modelo de desarrollo de la lección para la enseñanza centrado en grupos pequeños, que hace posible a todos los estudiantes lograr sus necesidades individuales en el aula. ¿Los resultados? Después de un año, los datos del estado revelaron que nuestros puntajes han crecido un 171 % en álgebra y un 107 % en literatura. (Aplausos) Tenemos un largo camino por recorrer, un muy largo camino por recorrer, pero ahora abordamos cada obstáculo con la actitud "¿Así es? Entonces, ¿qué hacemos?". Y eso me lleva a mi tercer y último lema. (Risas) Si nadie te dijo que te amaba hoy, recuerda que yo sí, y siempre lo haré. Mis estudiantes tienen problemas: problemas sociales, emocionales y económicos que Uds. nunca podrían imaginar. Algunos de ellos son sus propios padres, y algunos están completamente solos. Si alguien me pregunta mi verdadero secreto de cómo realmente mantengo progresando a Strawberry Mansion, tendría que decir que amo a mis estudiantes y creo en sus posibilidades incondicionalmente.
When I look at them, I can only see what they can become, and that is because I am one of them. I grew up poor in North Philadelphia too. I know what it feels like to go to a school that's not a school. I know what it feels like to wonder if there's ever going to be any way out of poverty. But because of my amazing mother, I got the ability to dream despite the poverty that surrounded me. So -- (Applause) -- if I'm going to push my students toward their dream and their purpose in life, I've got to get to know who they are. So I have to spend time with them, so I manage the lunchroom every day. (Laughter) And while I'm there, I talk to them about deeply personal things, and when it's their birthday, I sing "Happy Birthday" even though I cannot sing at all. (Laughter) I often ask them, "Why do you want me to sing when I cannot sing at all?" (Laughter) And they respond by saying, "Because we like feeling special." We hold monthly town hall meetings to listen to their concerns, to find out what is on their minds. They ask us questions like, "Why do we have to follow rules?" "Why are there so many consequences?" "Why can't we just do what we want to do?" (Laughter) They ask, and I answer each question honestly, and this exchange in listening helps to clear up any misconceptions. Every moment is a teachable moment. My reward, my reward for being non-negotiable in my rules and consequences is their earned respect. I insist on it, and because of this, we can accomplish things together. They are clear about my expectations for them,
Cuando los miro, solo puedo ver lo que pueden llegar a ser, y eso es porque yo soy uno de ellos. Crecí pobre también, en el norte de Filadelfia. Sé lo que se siente al ir a una escuela que no es una escuela. Sé lo que se siente preguntarse si hay alguna vez va a haber alguna manera de salir de la pobreza. Pero debido a mi increíble madre, tuve la capacidad de soñar a pesar de la pobreza que me rodeaba. Por lo tanto... (Aplausos) si voy a animar a mis estudiantes hacia su sueño y su propósito en la vida, tengo que llegar a saber quiénes son. Así que tengo que pasar tiempo con ellos, así que me las arreglo para ir al comedor todos los días. (Risas) Y ya que estoy allí, hablo con ellos acerca de cosas muy personales, y cuando es su cumpleaños, canto el "Feliz cumpleaños" a pesar de que no canto nada bien. (Risas) A menudo les pregunto, "¿Por qué quieres que cante si no sé cantar nada bien?". (Risas) Y ellos responden diciendo, "Porque nos gusta sentirnos especiales". Llevamos a cabo reuniones mensuales en la sala de juntas para escuchar sus preocupaciones, para averiguar lo que está en sus mentes. Ellos nos hacen preguntas como: "¿Por qué tenemos que seguir las reglas?". "¿Por qué hay tantas consecuencias?". "¿Por qué no podemos simplemente hacer lo que queramos?". (Risas) Ellos preguntan y yo respondo cada pregunta con honestidad, y este intercambio en la escucha ayuda a aclarar cualquier malentendido. Cada momento es un momento de aprendizaje. Mi recompensa, mi recompensa por ser no negociable en mis reglas y consecuencias es haberme ganado su respeto. Insisto en que, y debido a esto, podemos lograr cosas juntos. Ellos tienen claras mis expectativas para ellos,
and I repeat those expectations every day over the P.A. system. I remind them -- (Laughter) I remind them of those core values of focus, tradition, excellence, integrity and perseverance, and I remind them every day how education can truly change their lives. And I end every announcement the same: "If nobody told you they loved you today, you remember I do, and I always will." Ashley's words of "Miss, Miss, this is not a school," is forever etched in my mind. If we are truly going to make real progress in addressing poverty, then we have to make sure that every school that serves children in poverty is a real school, a school, a school -- (Applause) -- a school that provides them with knowledge and mental training to navigate the world around them. I do not know all the answers, but what I do know is for those of us who are privileged and have the responsibility of leading a school that serves children in poverty, we must truly lead, and when we are faced with unbelievable challenges, we must stop and ask ourselves, "So what. Now what? What are we going to do about it?" And as we lead, we must never forget that every single one of our students is just a child, often scared by what the world tells them they should be, and no matter what the rest of the world tells them they should be, we should always provide them with hope, our undivided attention, unwavering belief in their potential, consistent expectations, and we must tell them often, if nobody told them they loved them today, remember we do, and we always will. Thank you. (Applause) Thank you, Jesus.
y repito esas expectativas todos los días por los altoparlantes. Les recuerdo... (Risas) les recuerdo esos valores fundamentales de foco, tradición, excelencia, integridad y perseverancia, y les recuerdo todos los días cómo la educación puede cambiar verdaderamente la vida. Y termino cada anuncio igual: "Si nadie te dijo que te amaba hoy, recuerda que yo sí, y siempre lo haré". Las palabras de Ashley de "Señorita, señorita, esto no es una escuela", están grabadas en mi mente para siempre. Si realmente vamos a hacer progresos reales para hacer frente a la pobreza, entonces tenemos que asegurarnos de que cada escuela que atiende a niños en situación de pobreza sea una verdadera escuela, una escuela, una escuela... (Aplausos) una escuela que proporcione el conocimiento y el entrenamiento mental para navegar por el mundo que les rodea. No sé todas las respuestas, pero lo que sí sé es que aquellos de nosotros que somos privilegiados y tenemos la responsabilidad de dirigir una escuela que atiende a niños en situación de pobreza, debemos verdaderamente liderar, y cuando nos enfrentamos a desafíos increíbles, tenemos que parar y preguntarnos: "¿Así es? Entonces, ¿qué hacemos? ¿Qué vamos a hacer al respecto?". Y a medida que lideramos, nunca debemos olvidar que todos y cada uno de nuestros estudiantes son solo unos niños, a menudo asustados por lo que el mundo les dice qué deberían ser, y no importa lo que el resto del mundo les diga qué deberían ser, siempre debemos darles esperanza, toda nuestra atención, la creencia inquebrantable en su potencial, expectativas consistentes, y debemos decirles a menudo, si nadie les dijo hoy que los amaba, recuerden que nosotros sí, y siempre lo haremos. Gracias. (Aplausos) Gracias, Jesús.